## BEN **METZGER**

408.676.6277

https://www.linkedin.com/in/benpaulmetzger

benjpac@gmail.com

## **Summary**

Skilled QA Manager / Lead with experience in leading large teams to successfully test and launch products centered on mobile platforms, PC platforms, and other devices. Developed and drove technical analysis of products to match current and future customer needs with cost; then brought these products to market through the QA process. Managed budgets, hired and trained new employees, and mentored career paths.

#### **Technical Skills**

- JIRA
- Fogbugz
- Testlink
- Jenkins

- Agile
- SCRUM
- Bug triage
- Android studio tools

- Unix CLI
- SVN
- Microsoft Office

Applied experience in Python programming for build processes, and shell scripting in Android.

## Experience

QA Manager
QA Engineer
Nuance Communications

2014-2016

2011-2014

Seattle, WA

 Created and implemented test strategy for Swype keyboard product lines that balanced customer needs against risk assessment / revenue growth.

- Managed QA testing for over 400+ builds and releases, increasing project throughput from 40 in 2010 to 150 in 2016.
- Decreased software release cycle time in released OEM products by 74% by revamping test case management tool and implementing a smarter project-by-project risk assessment process.
- Developed a hiring and onboarding process that allowed us to quickly scale our QA team with our B2B needs. Hired 23 QA engineers with a very low turnover rate.
- Key player in the ramp up of a brand new office in Lucknow, India.
- Frequently provided coverage for OEM support to very demanding high cost / high stakes customers.
- Integral part of product development process for creating feedback on design and user experience of new features that were being designed and later developed.

# QA Lead Swype Inc (successful startup acquired by Nuance in 2011)

2010-2011 Seattle, WA

- Developed test plan for early stage startup with diverse set of product lines and large OEM customers including Samsung, LG, HTC, Nokia, HP and many more.
- Quality tested new features and bug fixes, interviewed and trained new team members, interfaced with OEM's, and managed build delivery to customers.
- Developed tiered and lightweight test processes to deliver nightly builds to Samsung and other global OEMs to seamlessly integrate into our customers' development pipeline.

### Education

#### Bachelor's Degree: Digital Technology & Culture

**Washington State University** 

Independent coursework completed in project management, leading / managing people, and python.